# Jing Li

(424)343-4236 • Jingli940731@gmail.com

2215 Rogene Drive, Apt. T3, Baltimore, MD, 21209

#### **Profile**

First-year master of science (ScM) candidate in Biostatistics interested in clinical genomics and business strategy development with undergraduate majors in Statistics and Biochemistry. Over 2 years' experience in R and obtained both SAS advanced and base certificate. Strong analytical backgrounds with experience of Kaggle competition using Random Forest and Boosting. Fluent in Mandarin and conversant in Japanese.

#### **Education**

# Master of Science (ScM) in Biostatistics, GPA: 4.00/4.00 Johns Hopkins University Bloomberg School of Public Health

September 2016-present Baltimore, MD

Relevant Coursework: Computational Genomics, Statistical Machine Learning, Principals and Methods of Functional Neuroimaging, Essentials of Probability and Statistical Inference, Methods in Biostatistics, Analysis of Longitudinal Data

# **Bachelor of Science in Statistics and Biochemistry,** GPA: 3.63/4.00 University of California Los Angeles

September 2012-June 2016

Los Angeles, CA

Honors: Alpha Lambda Delta and Phi Eta Sigma, Scholar-Athlete Award

#### Certificate

# SAS Advanced Programmer Certificate (AP016723v9)

March 2016

SAS Base Programmer Certificate (95%, Certificate No: BP056272v9) Certificate of Japanese-Language Proficiency Test N3 (N3A116471A)

January 2016 February 2015

## **Projects and Activities**

### **Kaggle Competition (Top7)**

Los Angeles, CA

Participant May, 2016

Kaggle is a platform for establishing data science competitions involving data mining, modeling and predicting

- Predicted animals' outcomes (euthanasia, adoption and etc.) for shelters in the Great Los Angeles area (both training and test data sets had over 110000 observations)
- Used data mining (wrote over 500 lines in R) to clean and reshape variables, and combined external data as potential predictors
- Selected predictors using cross validation and conducted multiple prediction models using Random Forest, Boosting, Multinomial Regression, Support Vector Machine, KNN as well as Neutral Networks
- Compared the prediction outcomes of all models based on log loss and established final ensemble classification models using Random Forest and Boosting

# Stats C183 Portfolio Project

Los Angeles, CA

Participant May, 2016

Stats C183 is about statistical models in finance and this project mainly concerned with optimal portfolio construction and portfolio performance

- Constructed portfolio with biotechnology and life insurance stocks
- Used single index model, constant correlation model and multi-group model to find the composition of optimum portfolios

• Analyzed and compared expected returns of each models corresponding to the market (S&P 500) using approaches such as Sharp Ratio, Differential Return as well as Treyor Measure

ASA Datafest
Los Angeles, CA
Participant
April 2016

ASA Datafest is a highly programming based data competition sponsored by American Statistical Association

- Implemented ticket pricing optimization strategy concerning with locations and events popularity based on data from Ticketmaster
- Quantified the popularity of events and established a classifier for events based on ticket values, number of tickets being sold as well as the popularity of events using R
- Conducted ANOVA test for the inter-city popularity difference and measured the significance ratio of the difference by TukeyHSD test as an index in the final pricing optimization model

#### **Experience**

InciteData Chengdu, China

Analyst Intern

July 2016-August 2016

InciteData is a technical company focusing on establishing automated big data analysis platform

- Cooperated with the team in conducting vehicle plate recognition algorithm using convolutional neural networks on TensorFlow
  - Tested run both softmax regression model and CNN model on Linux to check for precision of prediction

## **Sellmark Corporation**

Los Angeles, CA

**Business Analyst Intern** 

September 2015-Feburary 2016

Sellmark Corporation is a company carries hunting optics products

- Worked remotely to conduct statistical consulting based on orders and actual sales data using R
- Established a hybrid time series model combining ARIMA and multivariate regression for forecasting sales amount using R and Excel
  - Predicted the potentiality of new products using the hybrid time series model

## **Zhang's Dental Clinic**

San Jose, CA

**Assistant Intern** 

August 2014-September 2014

- Assisted dentists with scheduling appointments, taking X-ray, filling, cleaning and sterilizing instruments
- Managed over 5000 patients' profiles and helped file dental claims to insurance carriers

#### C-elegans' Research Lab

Los Angeles, CA

Student Researcher

April 2014-June 2014

C-elegans' research lab is supervised by Prof. Arisaka from UCLA to monitor behaviors of c-elegans under physical stimulation

- Researched relevant scientific literature and monitored C-elegans' behavior based on electrical stimulus
- Maintained C-elegans' growth and culturing by preparing agar as growth media and E.coli as food source

#### **Skills**

Computer: R (2 years+ experience)/SAS/Python/Tensorflow/SQL/Stata/SPSS/QGIS/Pymol/Lyx/Excel/Tableau Language: Fluent in Mandarin and conversant in Japanese